<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author>F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall</author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>  Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630. This digital project examines the German Political Reform movement and German political activity in New Orleans during the 1870s. While most of the articles focus directly on the German Political Reform movement, articles devoted to the German Republican Club are also included. Since the project specifically centers on German-New Orleanians’ activeness in Reconstruction politics, ads and other components of the newspapers are not included. As more newspapers are added, editorials and news will be prioritized over advertisements. </p>
               <p> This project currently incorporates articles from the two most prominent newspapers in Reconstruction New Orleans, the Daily-Picayune and the New Orleans Republican. German-language newspapers will be added as the project continues to grow. </p>
            <p> Editorial Notes: The current presentation is primarily in paragraph form. As the project grows, options to view the paper with the original page breaks will be available. German umlauts have been omitted by either Sophia Rouse or the newspaper's orignal editors. To adhere to the original text produced by the English-language papers, umlauts are not included in this project.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p> <bibl> F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall. "The Reform Movement," Daily-Picayune, 16  February 1870, https://www.newspapers.com/clip/119338774/the-reform-movement/, pg. 1 </bibl></p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head>The Reform Movement</head>
            <p>In connection with the article in last Sunday's <hi rend="italics">Picayune </hi>, on the reform movement inaugurated by a number of <name> German citizens </name>, whose names we gave, we publish to - day, in substance, the platform governing the <name ref="org001">German Political Reform Club </name>. </p>
         <p>It is made incumbent upon the members of the club to be untiring in their efforts, at the next and all other elections, to exclude from office corrupt and incapable legislators, partisan judges, and other unscrupulous officers, State and municipal, without regard to their politics, and to substitute for them men better qualified to discharge the duties of a public office. The voter, whether belonging to the <orgName ref="org003">Democratic</orgName> or <orgName ref="org002">Republican party </orgName>, shall act independent of the dic tates of party leaders, that he may learn to think and act in accordance with his own individual opinion, and cease to be a mere voting machine. A stop is to be put to fraud and corruption, which seek refuge behind the standard of the party, at all elections for municipal and State offices, for which the qualifications shall here after be ability, honesty and a full sense of the duties which such office may require. Political questions are to be excluded at elections of a purely local character. </p>
            <p>An equal and just distribution of taxes is demanded. The wealthy are to pay their taxes in equal proportion, and at the same time, with the middle classes. It must not occur again that the wealthy are in arrears with their taxes for ten years, and often longer, while the poor mechanic either voluntarily pays promptly, or is compelled to do so by the Sheriff. </p>
            <p> Public officers are to be strictly controlled, fraud and corruption to be exposed, and the guilty to be pun ished. </p>
         <p> <name ref="person054">The German citizens </name> further ask for representation in proportion taxation, which, in the language the platform, bad up to today never been accorded to them. They now demand to be represented in the legisla tive halls, in the State Government, on the judicial bench, and in the municipal administration; in short, have a voice in the administration our public affairs, which they ask not as a favor, but as a right to which they are entitled by virtue of their numbers and the large amount taxes they pay. Such are the features of the platform of the <name ref="org001"> German Political Reform Club </name>. We do not hesitate to pro nounce it a good one, and one, too, which is calculated to exercise strong moral pressure upon the ticket of both parties at the approaching nominations. </p>
            <p>The reform movement is gaining ground rapidly. It is, as we are most reliably informed, and authorized state by the President of the club, movement for reform in our public affairs solely, not a movement build up a "third party," as the impression seems to prevail. The leaders of this movement wish to influence the nominations to bo made, that good men, for whom every right thinking citizen can conscientiously vote, may be put on the ticket. Political issues should be lost sight and men of undoubted integrity should be nominated and elected office, without regard to political preferences, in accordance with the pro visions of their platform.</p> 
            <p>The importance of the movement should not be undervalued, especially as it may be productive much good.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
