<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author>F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall</author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630. This digital project examines the German Political Reform movement and German political activity in New Orleans during the 1870s. While most of the articles focus directly on the German Political Reform movement, articles devoted to the German Republican Club are also included. Since the project specifically centers on German-New Orleanians’ activeness in Reconstruction politics, ads and other components of the newspapers are not included. As more newspapers are added, editorials and news will be prioritized over advertisements. </p>
            <p> This project currently incorporates articles from the two most prominent newspapers in Reconstruction New Orleans, the Daily-Picayune and the New Orleans Republican. German-language newspapers will be added as the project continues to grow. </p>
            <p> Editorial Notes: The current presentation is primarily in paragraph form. As the project grows, options to view the paper with the original page breaks will be available. German umlauts have been omitted by either Sophia Rouse or the newspaper's orignal editors. To adhere to the original text produced by the English-language papers, umlauts are not included in this project.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p> F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall. “German Society Annual Meeting Last Night” The Times-Picayune, 9 June 1870, p.1. https://www.newspapers.com/clip/113110020/german-society-meeting-minutes-9-june-18/ </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          
            <head> German Society Annual Meeting Last Night </head>
         <p>  <name ref="org004"> The German society </name> for the protection of immigrants met last night in annual session, at<placeName ref="place005"> No. 51 Bienville street </placeName>. The meeting was called to order by the President, <persName ref="person034">Mr. Wm. de la Eue </persName>. The minutes of the previous annual meeting were read by the Secretary, <persName ref="person033"> Mr. Louis Schwaiz </persName>, after which <persName ref="person034"> Mr. de la Bue</persName> read the annual report for last year, of which the following is a synopsis. </p>
            <p> The report sets out with stating that, in accordance with resolutions passed at the last annual meeting, great exertions have been made toward enlarging the sphere of usefulness of the society. A committee appointed for this purpose, and composed of the following gentlemen,<persName type="leader">  E.'S. Wurzburger </persName>, <persName ref="person006"> Dr. T. Wentz </persName>, <persName ref="person029"> E. Stockmeyer Jr </persName> ., <persName ref="person051"> F.Eiokert </persName> and <persName ref="person007"> Jacob Hassinger </persName>, issued an address, in German and English, to the inhabitants of <placeName ref="place002">Louisiana</placeName>, in order to acquaint them with the intentions of the society and to secure their co-operation. At the same time this committee issued a circular addressed to agricultural laborers and mechanics who may be inclined to immigrate to the <placeName ref="place004">Southern States </placeName>, and especially to <placeName ref="place002">Louisiana</placeName>." Copies of this circular were sent to the principal emigration depots in <placeName type="country">Germany </placeName>, for general distribution. When these preliminary steps were completed, another committee composed of <persName ref="person030"> Messrs. E. S. Wurzburger </persName>. <persName ref="person007">Jacob Hassinger</persName> and <persName type="leader">F. Bickert</persName>, assembled to devise a plan for carrying into effect the purposes of the society. It was, however, ascertained that the means at the disposition of the society were not sufficient for carrying out its objects relative to enlarging the sphere of its usefulness. The committee recommended the establishing of an immigrant depot in a central locality of the city, blot the means for doing so were fonnd to be insufficient. It was then resolved to ask State aid, and several bills for this purpose were introduced at the last session of our State Legislature. One of them, appropriating $20,000 to the <name ref="org004"> German Society </name>, was adopted, but has not yet been signed by the Governor. the provisions of this bill are, however, such that they cannot be complied with by the <name ref="org004"> German Society</name>, Nevertheless the first step was taken, and it is to be hoped that at the next session of the Legislature the bill will be amended so that the <name ref="org004"> German Society </name> will be enabled to go to work. </p>
         <p>The report gives some interesting statistics on regard to German immigration, which shows a large increase over the preceding year. The arrivals at New Orleans in <date>1869-'70 </date> were 3700 Germans in 24 vessels, against 2436 in <date>1868-'69 </date>2212 came by way of <placeName ref="place006">Bremen</placeName>, and 1474 via <placeName ref="place007"> Hamburg </placeName>. The majority of these immigrants came by steamer. The treatment they received on board the <placeName ref="place007">Hamburg </placeName> and <placeName ref="place006">Bremen </placeName> steamships is spoken of very highly in the report, and the thanks of the <orgName ref="org004">German Society</orgName> are tendered to <persName ref="person029">Mr. E. F. Stockmeyer</persName>, the New Orleans agent of the North German Lloyd, and Messrs. Williams, Bapertiamp; Co., the agents of the Hamburg steamship line, for various courtesies. </p>
         <p>The majority of the immigrants arrived at this port last year, went to <placeName ref="place008">Texas</placeName> while a smaller number than in preceding years went td the West. The labor agency of the <orgName ref="org004">German Society</orgName> has proven a very useful institution, 2251 persons having obtained employment through thisagency last year. The finances of the <orgName ref="org004">German Society</orgName>are in a flourishing condition, the financial statement showing that the society has now a capital of $25,915 68 at its disposition. </p>
            <p>The report was unanimously adopted. </p>
             <cb/>  
         <p>The following officers for the current year were then elected by ballot <persName ref="person034">Wm. De la Rue </persName>, President; <persName ref="person035">F. Bickert </persName> , First Vice President; <persName ref="person036"> Charles Bendix </persName>, Second Vice President; <persName ref="person037"> Wm.B. Schmidt </persName>, Treasurer; <persName ref="person032">Louis Schwarz </persName>, Recording Secretary: <persName ref="person038"> F. Froh </persName>, Financial Secretary; <persName ref="person39">A. Bader, </persName> <persName ref="person029">E. Stockmeyer </persName>, <persName ref="person040"> Dr. B. Maas </persName> , <persName ref="person041"> J.Aschalck </persName>, <persName ref="person006"> Dr. E. Wentz </persName>, <persName ref="person030"> E.S. Wurzburger </persName>, <persName ref="person042">  H. Schmidt </persName>, <persName ref="person043"> A Bohne </persName>, <persName ref="peson031"> F. Oberheuser </persName>, <persName ref="person044">  D. Michel </persName>, <persName ref="person045">  G. Zalitz </persName>, directors. A twelfth director will be elected to night, there having been a tie vote. Messrs. <persName ref="person047">Louis Stein </persName>, <persName ref="person048">Moses</persName> and <persName ref="person046">Bickert, Jr.</persName>, were elected members of the commmittee of inspection. Messrs. <persName ref="person050"> Buhrman</persName> and <persName ref="person049"> N. Miller</persName> acted as commissioners of election.</p> 
            <p> After the result of the election had been announced, the meeting adjourned.</p>
        
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
