<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author>F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall </author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p> CITATION</p>
         </sourceDesc> 
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
       <div> <head> The German Reform Movement </head>
          <p> Pursuant to a call issued by the <name type="organziation">German Political Reform Club</name>, a large number of our <name type="ethnic-group">German citizens </name> met last night at the <placeName> Turner Hall, on Lafayette street </placeName>, to permanently organize themselves into a political body, whose objects are fully set forth in the platform governing them, which we publish below... The meeting was called to order by <persName type="leaders"> Mr. Jacob Hassinger </persName>, <persName type="leader">Mr. L. R. Jacoby </persName> acting as Secretary. <persName type="leader"> Mr. Hassinger</persName> stated briefly the object of the meeting inpermanent organization—and read the constitution and platform, of which the following are the principal features: </p>
         <p>It is made incumbent upon the members of the club to be untiring in their efforts, at the next and all other elections, to exclude from office corrupt and incapable legislators, partisan judges,and other unscrupulous officers, State and municipal, without regard to their politics, and to substitute for them better qualified to discharge the duties of a public office. The voter, whether belonging to the <name type="political-party"> Democratic or Republican party</name>, shall act independent of the dictates of party leaders, that he may learn to think and act in accordance with his own individual opinion, and cease to be a mere voting machine. A stop is to be put to fraud and cooperation which seek refuge behind the standard of the party, at all elections for municipal and State offices, for which the qualifications shall hereafter be ability, honesty and a full sense of the duties which such an office may require. Political questions are to be excluded at elections of a purely local character. An equal and just distribution of taxes is demanded.  The wealthy are to pay their taxes in equal proportion, and at the same time, with the middle classes. It must not occur again that the wealthy are in arrears with their taxes for ten years, and often longer, while the poor mechanic either voluntarily pays prompt compelled to do so by the Sheriff.</p> 
         <p>Public officers are to be strictly controlled, fraud and corruption to be exposed, and the guilty to be punished.</p>
         <p><name type="ethnic-group">The German citizens</name> further ask for representation in proportion to taxation, which had, up to-day, never been accorded to them. They now demand to be represented in the legislative halls, in the State government, on the judicial bench and in the municipal administration ; in short, to have a voice in the administration of our public affairs, which they ask not as a favor, but as a right which they are entitled by virtue of their numbers and the large amount of taxes they pay. </p>
         <p>Great and continued applause followed the reading of the platform, after which the Secretary read the names of those gentlemen that had, previous to the meeting last night, become members of the <name type="organziation">German Political Reform Club </name>.</p>
         <p>A resolution was then offered by <persName type="leader"> Mr. May </persName>, to the effect that only those gentlemen present who, by signing their names to the rolls, had become members of the organization, were entitled to participate in the proceedings, and calling upon all present to join 1n the movement by signing their names. During the recess which followed the adoption of this resolution, the lists for membership were numerously signed.</p>
         <p>The following resolution was then offered by <persName type="leader"> Dr. James Wentz </persName>, and unanimously adopted: </p> 
           <p> <hi rend="italic"> Be it Resolved</hi>, That no member of this 
            organization who is at the same time and 
            member of a State or parish committee, 
            or a member of any political club of any 
            of the now existing party organizations, 
            can be eligible to any office within the 
            organization known as the <name type="organziation"> German
            Political Reform Club </name>, or its auxiliary 
            clubs, so long as he holds an office
            in such State or parish committee, or as 
            long as he is a member of the <name type="organziation">political 
            club mentioned </name></p>
         <p>On motion to <persName type="leader">Mr. Kuhnholz </persName>, the meet- 
            ing then proceeded to the election of  
            permanent officers, with the following  
            result:  
            For President— <persName type="leader">Charles Potthoff </persName>
            For Vice President for the First District — <persName type="leader">Charles F. Buck. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Second District—<persName type="leader">George Merz. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Third District— <persName type="leader">F. Kuhnholz. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Fourth District— <persName type="leader">George Geier. </persName>
            For Recording Secretary— <persName type="leader">L. R. Jacoby. </persName>
            For Corresponding Secretary — <persName type="leader"> Ben Jarmbruster. </persName>
            For Treasurer— <persName type="leader">Dr. James Went </persName></p>
         <p><persName type="leader">Mr. Potthoft </persName>, the President elected by acclamation, was introduced to the meeting by <persName type="leader">Mr. Hassinger </persName>, and enthusiastically received. Taking the chair, <persName type="leader">Mr. Potthoff</persName> expressed, in a few brief remarks, his thanks for the honor conferred upon him, and gave the assurance that he would be untiring in his efforts to show himself worthy of the honor of having been chosen to preside over such an intelligent body of men. In conclusion, he warned those that had embarked in the reform meeting not to fall in any errors which would produce a German Know-Nothing party. Though <!-- add ethnciity German--> by birth, they were, by naturalization, citizens of this country, where all their interests are concentrated, and they must endeavor to act in concert with those of the native born citizens, who are alike opposed to the corruption prevailing in our public affairs, Five thousand German votes should be polled at the next election, and honest and capable men elected to office.</p>
         <p>Of the motion of Dr. Wentz the thanks of the meeting were voted for <persName type="leader"> Messrs. Jacob Hassinger</persName> <persName type="leader"> and Georg Foerster </persName> of the German Gazette for their strenous efforts in behalf of the reform movement.</p>
         <p>After a few remarks by <persName type="leader"> Messrs. Buck </persName>, <persName type="leader">Merz </persName> and <persName type="leader">Kuhnlholz </persName>, the following resolution was offered <persName type="leader">Mr. Sarre </persName> and adopted:</p>
          <p> <hi rend="italic"> Be it resolved </hi>: That each auxillary club shall be entitled to send one delegate to the <name type="organziation">Central Executive Committee </name> as soon as said auxiliary club shall have twenty-five members; provided that no auxiliary club shall be entitled to a representation of more than four delegates in the Central Executive Committee. A resolution offered by <persName type="leader"> Mr. Pabst </persName>, providing for general meetings to be called jointly by the President and the <name type="organziation">Central Executive Committee </name>, whenever found necessary, was also adopted. Another resolution provides for the organization of district clubs, with which duty the President and the several Vice Presidents are charged.</p>
         <p> <persName type="leader">Mr. Geo. Foerster </persName> then ottered a resolution to the effect that, immediately after its organization, the Central Executive Committee shall issue an address German. English and French, to the in population of the parishes of <placeName> Orleans and Jefferson </placeName>, explaining the principles and objects of the German Political Re form Club, and calling upon all honest and light minded citizens, without regard to their nationality and politics, to act in concert with the German citizens in forming a political reform party, and carrying out the principles bud down in the platform. On motion of <persName type="leader"> Mr. May, </persName> <persName type="leader">Messrs. J. Hassingeer </persName> and <persName type="leader">Geo.Foerster </persName> were elected ex-officio members of the <name type="organziation"> Central Executive Committee </name>, after which tbe meeting adjourned. </p>
          <p>The meeting, the proceedings of which were conducted entirely in German, was very orderly and harmonious, and the most prominent and respectable part of the <name type="ethnic-group"> German class </name> of our population were, last night, represented at <placeName> Turner's Hall </placeName>.</p> </div>
         
     
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
