<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The German Reform Movement</title>
            <title> Mass Meeting of our German Citizens at Turners' Hall</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p> Report from the <hi rend="italics">Daily-Picayune</hi> about <name type="organziation">German Political Reform Movement Meeting </name></p>
         </sourceDesc> 
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
       <div type="article">  <head> The German Reform Movement </head>
          <p> Pursuant to a call issued by the <name type="organziation">German Political Reform Club</name>, a large number of our <name type="ethnic-group">German citizens </name> met last night at the <placeName> Turner Hall, on Lafayette street </placeName>, to permanently organize themselves into a political body, whose objects are fully set forth in the platform governing them, which we publish below... The meeting was called to order by <persName type="leaders"> Mr. Jacob Hassinger </persName>, <persName type="leader">Mr. L. R. Jacoby </persName> acting as Secretary. <persName type="leader"> Mr. Hassinger</persName> stated briefly the object of the meeting inpermanent organization—and read the constitution and platform, of which the following are the principal features: </p>
         <p>It is made incumbent upon the members of the club to be untiring in their efforts, at the next and all other elections, to exclude from office corrupt and incapable legislators, partisan judges,and other unscrupulous officers, State and municipal, without regard to their politics, and to substitute for them better qualified to discharge the duties of a public office. The voter, whether belonging to the <name type="political-party"> Democratic or Republican party</name>, shall act independent of the dictates of party leaders, that he may learn to think and act in accordance with his own individual opinion, and cease to be a mere voting machine. A stop is to be put to fraud and cooperation which seek refuge behind the standard of the party, at all elections for municipal and State offices, for which the qualifications shall hereafter be ability, honesty and a full sense of the duties which such an office may require. Political questions are to be excluded at elections of a purely local character. An equal and just distribution of taxes is demanded.  The wealthy are to pay their taxes in equal proportion, and at the same time, with the middle classes. It must not occur again that the wealthy are in arrears with their taxes for ten years, and often longer, while the poor mechanic either voluntarily pays prompt compelled to do so by the Sheriff.</p> 
         <p>Public officers are to be strictly controlled, fraud and corruption to be exposed, and the guilty to be punished.</p>
         <p><name type="ethnic-group">The German citizens</name> further ask for representation in proportion to taxation, which had, up to-day, never been accorded to them. They now demand to be represented in the legislative halls, in the State government, on the judicial bench and in the municipal administration ; in short, to have a voice in the administration of our public affairs, which they ask not as a favor, but as a right which they are entitled by virtue of their numbers and the large amount of taxes they pay. </p>
         <p>Great and continued applause followed the reading of the platform, after which the Secretary read the names of those gentlemen that had, previous to the meeting last night, become members of the <name type="organziation">German Political Reform Club </name>.</p>
         <p>A resolution was then offered by <persName type="leader"> Mr. May </persName>, to the effect that only those gentlemen present who, by signing their names to the rolls, had become members of the organization, were entitled to participate in the proceedings, and calling upon all present to join 1n the movement by signing their names. During the recess which followed the adoption of this resolution, the lists for membership were numerously signed.</p>
         <p>The following resolution was then offered by <persName type="leader"> Dr. James Wentz </persName>, and unanimously adopted: </p> 
           <p> <hi rend="italic"> Be it Resolved</hi>, That no member of this 
            organization who is at the same time and 
            member of a State or parish committee, 
            or a member of any political club of any 
            of the now existing party organizations, 
            can be eligible to any office within the 
            organization known as the <name type="organziation"> German
            Political Reform Club </name>, or its auxiliary 
            clubs, so long as he holds an office
            in such State or parish committee, or as 
            long as he is a member of the <name type="organziation">political 
            club mentioned </name></p>
         <p>On motion to <persName type="leader">Mr. Kuhnholz </persName>, the meet- 
            ing then proceeded to the election of  
            permanent officers, with the following  
            result:  
            For President— <persName type="leader">Charles Potthoff </persName>
            For Vice President for the First District — <persName type="leader">Charles F. Buck. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Second District—<persName type="leader">George Merz. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Third District— <persName type="leader">F. Kuhnholz. </persName>
            For Vice President for the Fourth District— <persName type="leader">George Geier. </persName>
            For Recording Secretary— <persName type="leader">L. R. Jacoby. </persName>
            For Corresponding Secretary — <persName type="leader"> Ben Jarmbruster. </persName>
            For Treasurer— <persName type="leader">Dr. James Went </persName></p>
         <p><persName type="leader">Mr. Potthoft </persName>, the President elected by acclamation, was introduced to the meeting by <persName type="leader">Mr. Hassinger </persName>, and enthusiastically received. Taking the chair, <persName type="leader">Mr. Potthoff</persName> expressed, in a few brief remarks, his thanks for the honor conferred upon him, and gave the assurance that he would be untiring in his efforts to show himself worthy of the honor of having been chosen to preside over such an intelligent body of men. In conclusion, he warned those that had embarked in the reform meeting not to fall in any errors which would produce a German Know-Nothing party. Though <!-- add ethnciity German--> by birth, they were, by naturalization, citizens of this country, where all their interests are concentrated, and they must endeavor to act in concert with those of the native born citizens, who are alike opposed to the corruption prevailing in our public affairs, Five thousand German votes should be polled at the next election, and honest and capable men elected to office.</p>
         <p>Of the motion of Dr. Wentz the thanks of the meeting were voted for <persName type="leader"> Messrs. Jacob Hassinger</persName> <persName type="leader"> and Georg Foerster </persName> of the German Gazette for their strenous efforts in behalf of the reform movement.</p>
         <p>After a few remarks by <persName type="leader"> Messrs. Buck </persName>, <persName type="leader">Merz </persName> and <persName type="leader">Kuhnlholz </persName>, the following resolution was offered <persName type="leader">Mr. Sarre </persName> and adopted:</p>
          <p> <hi rend="italic"> Be it resolved </hi>: That each auxillary club shall be entitled to send one delegate to the <name type="organziation">Central Executive Committee </name> as soon as said auxiliary club shall have twenty-five members; provided that no auxiliary club shall be entitled to a representation of more than four delegates in the Central Executive Committee. A resolution offered by <persName type="leader"> Mr. Pabst </persName>, providing for general meetings to be called jointly by the President and the <name type="organziation">Central Executive Committee </name>, whenever found necessary, was also adopted. Another resolution provides for the organization of district clubs, with which duty the President and the several Vice Presidents are charged.</p>
         <p> <persName type="leader">Mr. Geo. Foerster </persName> then ottered a resolution to the effect that, immediately after its organization, the Central Executive Committee shall issue an address German. English and French, to the in population of the parishes of <placeName> Orleans and Jefferson </placeName>, explaining the principles and objects of the German Political Re form Club, and calling upon all honest and light minded citizens, without regard to their nationality and politics, to act in concert with the German citizens in forming a political reform party, and carrying out the principles bud down in the platform. On motion of <persName type="leader"> Mr. May, </persName> <persName type="leader">Messrs. J. Hassingeer </persName> and <persName type="leader">Geo.Foerster </persName> were elected ex-officio members of the <name type="organziation"> Central Executive Committee </name>, after which tbe meeting adjourned. </p>
          <p>The meeting, the proceedings of which were conducted entirely in German, was very orderly and harmonious, and the most prominent and respectable part of the <name type="ethnic-group"> German class </name> of our population were, last night, represented at <placeName> Turner's Hall </placeName>.</p> </div>
         
         <div type="New-Article"> <head>"The German Society of New Orleans" </head>
            <p> We have already mentioned that the bill which was introduced at the last session of the Legislature, by Hon. L. A. Wilts, entitled" an act to aid the <name type="organziation"> German Society of New Orleans </name>to establish a house of reception for immigrants under the Veaspices of that society," has become a law by the signature of <persName type="politican"> Gov. Warmoth </persName>. The bill appropriates the sum of $20,000 to the <name type="organziation"> German Society </name>, in consideration of which this organization is to erect an immigrant depot at a cost of not less than $30,000. This and other provisions set forth in the bill are to be complied with before the State aid of $20,000 tan be claimed.</p>
            <p> We learn that steps have already been taken by the <name type="organziation"> German Sooiety </name> looking toward the realization of the project facilitated by the opportune State aid and also tending toward inducing the Legislature to still farther promote the cause of immigration by placing the <name type="organziation"> German Society </name> financially in a condition which would extend the sphere of its usefulness. </p>
            <p> At a meeting of the <placeName type="directors">Board of Directors of the German Society </placeName>, a few days since, it was resolved that a committee com posed of the President, Vice President and secretary of the society be appointed, whose duty it shall be to select a suitable site for the proposed immigrant depot. Another resolution was adopted directing the President of the society to appoint a committee of three, whose duty it shall be to induce the Legislature to authorize the division of the present head tax upon immigrants arriving at our port equally between the <name type="organziation">German Society </name> and the <name type="organziation">Charity Hospital </name> </p>
                    <p> Should the legislature acquiesce in this proposition, there appears to be no doubt that the pecuniary aid thus extended would be productive of good, by enabling tnegierman oociety, wniou, as our readers know, is an entirely benevo lent organization, to more efficiently pro mote immigration to our State. It would in course of time furthermore do away with that expensive and useless institution, the "Bureau of Emigration," which dot draws the money derived from the head tax on immigrants, with ont giving any equivalent for it. The German Society of New Orleans "has, ever since its organization, in 1847, faithfully labored in behalf of indigent immigrants, by graciously procuring employment for them and otherwise as slating them, and, in view of its past services, is surely entitled to some consideration. </p>
         </div>
    
      
         </div>
         <div type="new-article"> <head> Address of the German Political Association</head>
            <p>To Our Fellow Citizens: In order to remove and dispel the misconceptions which exist, and the erroneous impressions which are circulated, through ignorance or malice, for the purpose of perverting the avowed objects of the "German Political Reform Association," this body places itself clearly and fairly before those interested in the welfare of our city and State, and "without equivocation or reserve," submits to the people of New Orleans and of Louisiana, in addition to, and for the further exposition of the platform and constitution already published, the following explanations. </p>
               <p> 1. Our organization is not a political party, but simply an association of citizens, as its name implies, uniting their efforts aud their influence for the purpose of bringing about a reform in the administration of our parish, municipal and state governments, and to endeavor at the next and at all subsequent elections forever to close the halls of legislation, the bureau of State and city government, and the temples of justice, against those who are corrupt, incompetent and unscrupulous, and to open them to those who are just, honorable aud able, irrespective of party politics; to demand a just division and impartial collection of taxes— the rich speculator, the big merchant, the powerful corporation shall not be permitted to remain in arrears, while the retailer, the poor middle man, is compelled to pay or suffer the injury and disgrace of a sheriffs. </p>
              <p> 2. This reform is sought to be effected by eschewing "party politics" from our local affiirs—striking the words "Democrat" or "Republican" from the list of qualifications for local or State offices as meaningless and insignificant, and recognizing no claims or qualifications to office but such as are based upon personal merit, honesty and worth.</p>
            <p>3. The <name type="organziation">" German Political Reform Association"</name>denies in unqualified terms the chargo brought against it. of attempting to create a 'German Party," national and exclusive; it has no other object but those already expressed, and is "German" only for the purpose of uniting the German population on the side of Reform, whenever and under whatever standard it may appear. </p>
            <p>   4. The <name type="organziation">"German Political Reform Association" </name> do indeed hope and desire, and it will be one of its objects, that a Union of all good citizens, a "Party," if it so pleases, shall be created, which will adopt the plan aud platform of this association. It is for this purpose that these explanations are made, to convince the citizens of New Orleans that we propose to build on a liberal and extensive basis, and "to make our vaunting true," we respectfully invite participation in our movement, and suggest the formation of co operative organizations among all classes of citizens. Whv do not those good and well disposed citizens, who favored the intentions of the Taxpavers' Association, come forward and act with us. Our aims are identical, our interests the same. We desire prosperity— so do you. We do nothing as Germans—everything as your fellow-citizeus. We desire to preserve the honor, the welfare. the reputation of our State and city. Every true citizen can want nothing less. We wish to secure a faithful aud economical government, whose most sacred object shall be to render the people happy and contented, strong in their fait a and hopeful with the assurance of continues prosperity—and surely no good man and citizen will "hesitate to give his support to an undertaking which promises so much good. </p>
            <p>  Fifth, and lastly, it is particularly understood that no member of the <name type="organziation">"Reform Association!" </name> shall be in any manner compromised as to his national aud federal politics. Such are our principles, or aims, our objects. But we do not believg ourselves able to accomplish them without the support of every good citizen. We appeal, therefore, to the whole population of the State and city—native and foreign-born, to join the Reform Association. Let all honest men unite, and with zealous and systematic labor, we will soon place the Control of our affairs into the hands of faithful, capable and trustworthy men, having the welfare of the community and the happiness and prosperity of the people at heart. <placeName type="city">New Orleans </placeName>, <date>March 12, 1870 </date>. the central executive committee of the GERMAN POLITICAL REFORM ASSOCIATION.</p>
            <p>  <persName type="leader">Charles Potthoff, President. </persName>
               <persName type= "leader"> Charles F. Back, Vice President, First District. </persName>
               <persName type= "leader"> George Merz, Vice President, Second District. </persName>
               <persName type= "leader"> F- Kuhnholz, Vice President, Third District. </persName>
               <persName type= "leader"> George Geir, Vice President, Fourth District. </persName>
               <persName type= "leader"> Dr. Wenz </persName> Treasurer, <persName>Jacob Hassioger </persName>, <persName type= "leader">George Foerster </persName>, <persName type= "leader"> R. Hummel </persName>,<persName type= "leader"> M. F. Sibilsky </persName>, <persName type= "leader">Conrad Streeder </persName>, delegates, First District.
               <persName type= "leader">George Nangesser </persName>,  <persName type= "leader"> C. Bambach </persName>,  <persName type= "leader"> J. A. Schaick </persName>,  <persName type= "leader"> William Frommeyer </persName>,  <persName type= "leader"> Wiliiam Vttllott </persName>,  <persName type= "leader"> Charles May </persName>, delegates, Second District. 
               <persName type= "leader">  Charles Ziegler </persName>,  <persName type= "leader">John Ueber </persName>, delegates, Third District.
               <persName>Otto Briede </persName>, <persName type= "leader">Julius Reusch</persName>, delegates. Fourth District.
               <persName type= "leader"> Benjamin Armbruster </persName>, Corresponding Secretary. <persName> L. R Jacoby </persName>, Recording Secretary.</p>
         
         </div>
         <div type="new-article"> <head>The Reform Movement</head>
            <p>In connection with the article in last Sunday's <hi rend="italics">Picayune </hi>, on the reform movement inaugurated by a number of <name> <!--figure out how to refer to them--> German citizens </name>, whose names we gave, we publish to - day, in substance, the platform governing the <name type="organization">German Political Reform Club </name>. </p>
               <p>It is made incumbent upon the members of the club to be untiring in their efforts, at the next and all other elections, to exclude from office corrupt and incapable legislators, partisan judges, and other unscrupulous officers, State and municipal, without regard to their politics, and to sub stitute for them men better qualified to discharge the duties of a public office. The voter, whether belonging to the Democratic or Republican party, shall act independent of the dic tates of party leaders, that he may learn to think and act in accordance with his own individual opinion, and cease to be a mere voting machine. A stop is to be put to fraud and corruption, which seek refuge behind the standard of the party, at all elections for municipal and State offices, for which the qualifications shall here after be ability, honesty and a full sense of the duties which such office may require. Political questions are to be excluded at elections of a purely local character. </p>
                  <p>An equal and just distribution of taxes is demanded. The wealthy are to pay their taxes in equal propor tion, and at the same time, with the middle classes. It must not occur again that the wealthy are in arrears with their taxes for ten years, and often longer, while the poor mechanic either voluntarily pays promptly, or is compelled to do so by the Sheriff. </p>
                     <p> Public officers are to be strictly controlled, fraud and corruption to be exposed, and the guilty to be pun ished. </p>
            <p> The German citizens further ask for representation in proportion taxation, which, in the language the platform, bad up to today never been accorded to them. They now demand to be represented in the legisla tive halls, in the State Government, on the judicial bench, and in the municipal administration; in short, have a voice in the administration our public affairs, which they ask not as a favor, but as a right to which they are entitled by virtue of their numbers and the large amount taxes they pay. Such are the features of the platform of the <name type="organization"> German Political Reform Club </name>. We do not hesitate to pro nounce it a good one, and one, too, which is calculated to exercise strong moral pressure upon the ticket of both parties at the approaching nominations. </p>
                      <p>The reform movement is gaining ground rapidly. It is, as we are most reliably informed, and authorized state by the President of the club, movement for reform in our public affairs solely, not a movement build up a "third party," as the impression seems to prevail. The leaders of this movement wish to influence the nominations to bo made, that good men, for whom every right thinking citizen can conscientiously vote, may be put on the ticket. Political issues should be lost sight and men of undoubted integrity should be nominated and elected office, without regard to political preferences, in accordance with the pro visions of their platform.</p> 
                         <p>The importance of the movement should not be undervalued, especially as it may be productive much good.</p></div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
