<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="out/Class.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title> German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author> S.L. Brown and Co.</author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>  Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630. This digital project examines the German Political Reform movement and German political activity in New Orleans during the 1870s. While most of the articles focus directly on the German Political Reform movement, articles devoted to the German Republican Club are also included. Since the project specifically centers on German-New Orleanians’ activeness in Reconstruction politics, ads and other components of the newspapers are not included. As more newspapers are added, editorials and news will be prioritized over advertisements. </p>
            <p> This project currently incorporates articles from the two most prominent newspapers in Reconstruction New Orleans, the Daily-Picayune and the New Orleans Republican. German-language newspapers will be added as the project continues to grow. </p>
            <p> Editorial Notes:The current presentation is in paragraph form. As the project grows, options to view the paper with the original columns and page breaks will be available. German umlauts have been omitted by either Sophia Rouse or the newspaper's orignal editors. To adhere with the original text produced by the English-language papers, umlauts are not included in this project.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p><bibl> S.L. Brown and Co. "The German Republicans. New Orleans, September 1876" New Orleans Republican, 12 September 1876. https://www.newspapers.com/clip/119397626/german-republican-club/ pg. 3 </bibl></p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head> The German Republicans. New Orleans, September 11,1876</head>
         <p> <persName type="editor"> Editor Republican </persName>: I notice in last Sunday's <hi rend="italiac">Picayune </hi> an article entitled "The Germans and Mr. Packard," signed by <quote>"one whose Republicanism can not be questioned." </quote> </p>
         <p>This gentleman asserts that there is a feeling of decided hostility existing in the city among German Republicans against <persName ref="person025"> Mr. Packard </persName> because he had given already unquestionable evidence that he would not, now, nor alter his election as Governor, give any representation or patronage to citzens of German nationality or extraction. He further says that the German Republicans were sick of this and were going to vote the State ticket with <persName ref="person055"> Nicholls and Co. </persName> on it, and the national ticket with <persName ref="person056">Hayes</persName> and <persName type="vice-president"> Wheeler </persName>. He even goes so far as to say the dissatislaction was so great that at the meet in» next Monday night (the eleventh) at <placeName> Mechanics' Institute </placeName>, at the <name ref="org005"> German Republican Central Club </name>, a strong resolution repudiating <persName ref="person025"> Captain Packard </persName>  would be introduced. Now, this is all nonsense. Has the gentleman not seen in Saturday's Republican a resolution passed by the <name ref="org005">German Republican Central Club </name>, and forwarded to the parish executive committee, pledging our adherence to the party as  German-American Republicans, and our unqualified support of both national and State ticket» </p>
         <p>No German Republican who has got his five senses can vote any other ticket than the Republican straight through, even if there should be one or the other candidate not exactly to his liking. Does he believe that the Germans, who are generally of a peace and order-loving disposition, win vote for <persName ref="person033">General Nicholls </persName>, who now, on his <quote>"swinging around the circle" </quote>tour, has men in his retinue who openly preach murder and riot? He is greatly mistaken. I venture to say that a great number ot Germans who are now hob-nobbiog with the Democratic party will certainly, on the seventh of November next, vote the Republican ticket, and, if need be, on the sly. </p>
         <p>As far as the refusal recognition and patronage by <persName ref="person025"> Mr. Packard </persName> to German American citizens is concerned, I can speak only for the <name ref="org005">German Republican Central Club </name>. This club was not organized for a money-making nor position-seeking purpose. Its officers members have not even made the personal acquaintance of  <persName ref="person025">Mr. Packard </persName>, less have they asked him, or anybody else, for some offices, consequently could not have been refused. <persName>Mr. Packard's </persName> character as a true Republican and a gentleman stands too high man Republicans as that bring discord among the members of the <name ref="org005"> <orgName type="political-party">German Republican Central Club </orgName> </name>, as the <quote> "gentleman whose Republicanism can not be doubted.' </quote>
            <persName ref="person026"> E. Boedicke </persName>, Secretary <name ref="org005">German Republican Central Club </name>.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
