<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href=https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sophiarouse6/HIST-630/main/Class.ODD>
<?xml-model href="out/Class.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author>S.L. Brown and Co.</author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630. This digital project examines the German Political Reform movement and German political activity in New Orleans during the 1870s. While most of the articles focus directly on the German Political Reform movement, articles devoted to the German Republican Club are also included. Since the project specifically centers on German-New Orleanians’ activeness in Reconstruction politics, ads and other components of the newspapers are not included. As more newspapers are added, editorials and news will be prioritized over advertisements. </p>
 <p> This project currently incorporates articles from the two most prominent newspapers in Reconstruction New Orleans, the Daily-Picayune and the New Orleans Republican. German-language newspapers will be added as the project continues to grow. </p>
            <p> Editorial Notes: The current presentation is primarily in paragraph form. As the project grows, options to view the paper with the original page breaks will be available. German umlauts have been omitted by either Sophia Rouse or the newspaper's orignal editors. To adhere to the original text produced by the English-language papers, umlauts are not included in this project.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>S.L. Brown and Co. "Address of the German Political Association," New Orleans Republican, 11 January 1871, https://www.newspapers.com/clip/119336358/address-of-the-german-political-reform-a/, pg. 1</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head> Address of the German Political Association</head>
         <p>To Our Fellow Citizens: In order to remove and dispel the misconceptions which exist, and the erroneous impressions which are circulated, through ignorance or malice, for the purpose of perverting the avowed objects of the <name ref="org001"> "German Political Reform Association,"</name> this body places itself clearly and fairly before those interested in the welfare of our city and State, and "without equivocation or reserve," submits to the people of New Orleans and of Louisiana, in addition to, and for the further exposition of the platform and constitution already published, the following explanations. </p>
            <p> 1. Our organization is not a political party, but simply an association of citizens, as its name implies, uniting their efforts aud their influence for the purpose of bringing about a reform in the administration of our parish, municipal and state governments, and to endeavor at the next and at all subsequent elections forever to close the halls of legislation, the bureau of State and city government, and the temples of justice, against those who are corrupt, incompetent and unscrupulous, and to open them to those who are just, honorable aud able, irrespective of party politics; to demand a just division and impartial collection of taxes— the rich speculator, the big merchant, the powerful corporation shall not be permitted to remain in arrears, while the retailer, the poor middle man, is compelled to pay or suffer the injury and disgrace of a sheriffs. </p>
            <p> 2. This reform is sought to be effected by eschewing "party politics" from our local affiirs—striking the words "Democrat" or "Republican" from the list of qualifications for local or State offices as meaningless and insignificant, and recognizing no claims or qualifications to office but such as are based upon personal merit, honesty and worth.</p>
            <p>3. The <name ref="org001">"German Political Reform Association"</name>denies in unqualified terms the charges brought against it. of attempting to create a 'German Party," national and exclusive; it has no other object but those already expressed, and is "German" only for the purpose of uniting the German population on the side of Reform, whenever and under whatever standard it may appear. </p>
         <p>   4. The <name ref="org001">"German Political Reform Association" </name> do indeed hope and desire, and it will be one of its objects, that a Union of all good citizens, a "Party," if it so pleases, shall be created, which will adopt the plan aud platform of this association. It is for this purpose that these explanations are made, to convince the citizens of <placeName ref="placce001">New Orleans</placeName>that we propose to build on a liberal and extensive basis, and "to make our vaunting true," we respectfully invite participation in our movement, and suggest the formation of co operative organizations among all classes of citizens. Whv do not those good and well disposed citizens, who favored the intentions of the <name ref="org007">Taxpavers' Association </name>, come forward and act with us. Our aims are identical, our interests the same. We desire prosperity— so do you. We do nothing as Germans—everything as your fellow-citizens. We desire to preserve the honor, the welfare. the reputation of our State and city. Every true citizen can want nothing less. We wish to secure a faithful aud economical government, whose most sacred object shall be to render the people happy and contented, strong in their fait a and hopeful with the assurance of continues prosperity—and surely no good man and citizen will "hesitate to give his support to an undertaking which promises so much good. </p>
         <p>  Fifth, and lastly, it is particularly understood that no member of the <name ref="org001">"Reform Association!" </name> shall be in any manner compromised as to his national aud federal politics. Such are our principles, or aims, our objects. But we do not believg ourselves able to accomplish them without the support of every good citizen. We appeal, therefore, to the whole population of the State and city—native and foreign-born, to join the <name ref="org001">Reform Association </name>. Let all honest men unite, and with zealous and systematic labor, we will soon place the control of our affairs into the hands of faithful, capable and trustworthy men, having the welfare of the community and the happiness and prosperity of the people at heart. <placeName ref="place001">New Orleans </placeName>, <date>March 12, 1870 </date>. the central executive committee of the <name ref="org001">GERMAN POLITICAL REFORM ASSOCIATION </name>.</p>
       <cb/>
         <p> <persName ref="person001"> Charles Potthoff, President</persName>  </p>
            <p>  <persName ref="person002"> Charles F. Buck, Vice President, First District </persName> </p>
             <p> <persName ref="person003"> George Merz, Vice President, Second District. </persName> </p>
            <p>  <persName ref="person004"> F- Kuhnholz, Vice President, Third District. </persName> </p>
             <p>  <persName ref="person005"> George Geir, Vice President, Fourth District. </persName></p>
         <p>  <persName ref="person006"> Dr. Wenz </persName> Treasurer, <persName ref="person007">Jacob Hassioger </persName>, <persName ref="person008">George Foerster </persName>, <persName  ref="person009"> R. Hummel </persName>,<persName ref="person010"> M. F. Sibilsky </persName>, <persName ref="person011">Conrad Streeder </persName>, delegates, First District.
            <persName ref="person022">George Nangesser </persName>,  <persName ref="person012"> C. Bambach </persName>,  <persName ref="person013"> J. A. Schaick </persName>,  <persName ref="person014"> William Frommeyer </persName>,  <persName ref="person015"> Wiliiam Vollott </persName>,  <persName ref="person016"> Charles May </persName>, delegates, Second District. </p>
         <p> <persName ref="person023">  Charles Ziegler </persName>,  <persName ref="person017">John Ueber </persName>, delegates, Third District. </p>
         <p> <persName ref="person018">Otto Briede </persName>, <persName ref="person019">Julius Reusch</persName>, delegates. Fourth District. </p>
         <p> <persName ref="person020"> Benjamin Armbruster </persName>, Corresponding Secretary. <persName ref="person021"> L. R Jacoby </persName>, Recording Secretary.</p> 
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
