<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<?xml-model href="../../out/Class.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../../out/Class.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>German Politics in Reconstruction New Orleans</title> <author>F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall</author>
            <respStmt> <resp> Editor </resp>  <name> Sophia Rouse </name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Created for Digital Humanities HIST 630. This digital project examines the German Political Reform movement and German political activity in New Orleans during the 1870s. While most of the articles focus directly on the German Political Reform movement, articles devoted to the German Republican Club are also included. Since the project specifically centers on German-New Orleanians’ activeness in Reconstruction politics, ads and other components of the newspapers are not included. As more newspapers are added, editorials and news will be prioritized over advertisements. </p>
               <p> This project currently incorporates articles from the two most prominent newspapers in Reconstruction New Orleans, the Daily-Picayune and the New Orleans Republican. German-language newspapers will be added as the project continues to grow. </p>
               <p> Editorial Notes:The current presentation is in paragraph form. As the project grows, options to view the paper with the original page breaks will be available. German umlauts have been omitted by either Sophia Rouse or the newspaper's orignal editors. To adhere with the original text produced by the English-language papers, umlauts are not included in this project.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p> F.A. Lumsden and G.W. Kendall. "The German Society of New Orleans," Daily-Picayune, 11 January 1871, p. 1,  https://www.newspapers.com/clip/113195315/the-german-society-of-new-orleans/</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
            <head>"The German Society of New Orleans" </head> 
            <p> We have already mentioned that the bill which was introduced at the last session of the Legislature, by <name ref="person052">Hon. L. A. Wilts </name>, entitled <quote>"an act to aid the <name ref="org004"> German Society of New Orleans </name>to establish a house of reception for immigrants under the Veaspices of that society," </quote> has become a law by the signature of <persName ref="person053"> Gov. Warmoth </persName>. The bill appropriates the sum of $20,000 to the <name type="organziation"> German Society </name>, in consideration of which this organization is to erect an immigrant depot at a cost of not less than $30,000. This and other provisions set forth in the bill are to be complied with before the State aid of $20,000 tan be claimed.</p>
            <p> We learn that steps have already been taken by the <name ref="org004"> German Sooiety </name> looking toward the realization of the project facilitated by the opportune State aid and also tending toward inducing the Legislature to still farther promote the cause of immigration by placing the <name ref="org004"> German Society </name> financially in a condition which would extend the sphere of its usefulness. </p>
            <p> At a meeting of the <placeName ref="org004">Board of Directors of the German Society </placeName>, a few days since, it was resolved that a committee com posed of the President, Vice President and secretary of the society be appointed, whose duty it shall be to select a suitable site for the proposed immigrant depot. Another resolution was adopted directing the President of the society to appoint a committee of three, whose duty it shall be to induce the Legislature to authorize the division of the present head tax upon immigrants arriving at our port equally between the <name ref="org004">German Society </name> and the Charity Hospital</p>
         <p> Should the legislature acquiesce in this proposition, there appears to be no doubt that the pecuniary aid thus extended would be productive of good, by enabling tnegierman oociety, wniou, as our readers know, is an entirely benevo lent organization, to more efficiently pro mote immigration to our State. It would in course of time furthermore do away with that expensive and useless institution, the "Bureau of Emigration," which draws the money derived from the head tax on immigrants, with ont giving any equivalent for it. <name ref="org004">The German Society of New Orleans </name> <quote>"has, ever since its organization, in <date>1847</date>, faithfully labored in behalf of indigent immigrants, by graciously procuring employment for them and otherwise as slating them, and in view of its past services, is surely entitled to some consideration." </quote> </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
